Guide to the Reuben A. Holden, Secretary of Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Reuben A. Holden, secretary of Yale University, records
1901-1972
RU 19
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
145.25
The records primarily document the ongoing functions of the Yale secretary's office, 1953-1971, during Reuben A. Holden's tenure as secretary. Series III includes the materials most closely associated with these functions, such as comprehensive files of annual and special reports, as well as documentation on Yale commencement ceremonies, honorary degree recipients, lectureships, prizes and scholarships, the university council committee, buildings dedication and use, and special events at Yale or in conjunction with New Haven, Connecticut. Series II more generally consists of materials on alumni activities, the Yale Corporation, academic departments, professional schools, Yale institutes, and various standing and ad hoc committees and councils. Series II also includes general alphabetical correspondence files. The records included in Series I document Holden's years as assistant to the president and associate secretary during 1947-1953, especially his involvement with alumni relations.
Yale University. Office of the Secretary
Holden, Reuben A. (Reuben Andrus), 1918-
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 4-A (YRG 4-A), Records of the Yale secretary's office.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is partially restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged as follows: I. Assistant to the President and Associate Secretary: Subject-Correspondence File, 1931-1972. II. University Secretary: General Correspondence and Subject File, 1901-1972. III. University Secretary: Subject File, 1929-1971. IV. General Correspondence and Subject File, 1911-1971.
Scope and Contents
The records primarily document the ongoing functions of the Yale secretary's office, 1953-1971, during Reuben A. Holden's tenure as secretary. Series III includes the materials most closely associated with these functions, such as comprehensive files of annual and special reports, as well as documentation on Yale commencement ceremonies, honorary degree recipients, lectureships, prizes and scholarships, the university council committee, buildings dedication and use, and special events at Yale or in conjunction with New Haven, Connecticut. Series II more generally consists of materials on alumni activities, the Yale Corporation, academic departments, professional schools, Yale institutes, and various standing and ad hoc committees and councils. Series II also includes general alphabetical correspondence files. The records included in Series I document Holden's years as assistant to the president and associate secretary during 1947-1953, especially his involvement with alumni relations.
Commencement ceremonies; Degrees, Academic; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Alumni and alumnae; Yale University -- Awards; Yale University -- Buildings; Yale University -- Degrees; Yale University -- Public relations; Yale Corporation; Yale University. Office of the Secretary
- Assistant to the President and Associate Secretary: Subject Correspondence Files, 1931-1972 (bulk: 1947-1953); Series I
  - Academic freedom, 1949-1953 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Admissions and enrollment: inquiries and complaints, 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Admissions, 1952-1953 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Airplane accident, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Air Science and Tactics, Department of, 1950-1953 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Alpha Phi Omega, 1947-1952 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Alumni, Local Associations of, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Alumni Board
    - 1947-1953 (Box 2, Folder 9-12)
    - College affiliates, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Committee on Written Material, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Members, 1946-1949 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Reports, 1947-1952 (Box 2, Folder 16-18)
    - Reports and minutes, 1952-1953 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Survey Committee, 1951-1952 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Alumni Day, 1948-1953 (Box 3, Folder 21-23)
  - Alumni fellow candidates, 1949-1951 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Alumni Fund, 1951-1954 (Box 3, Folder 25-26)
  - Alumni Fund: annual reports of, 1947-1951 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Alumni Magazine, 1948-1952 (Box 3, Folder 28-29)
  - Alumni Records, Office of, 1948-1954 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Alumni Relations: suggestions for improvement of, 1947-1949 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Alumni Relations: Western States Committees on, 1947-1948 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Alumni trips, 1952-1953 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - American Alumni Council
    - 1947-1953 (Box 4, Folder 34-36)
    - publications, 1947-1948 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Angell, President Emeritus James R., 1949 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Anniversaries, 1947-1951 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Anniversary, Yale's Two Hundred and Fiftieth, 1951-1952 (Box 4, Folder 40-41)
  - Anniversary, Yale's Two Hundred and Fiftieth: press and magazine releases, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Arkansas, Yale Club of, 1948-1950 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Art and Architecture, School of, 1951-1953 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Art Gallery, 1951-1953 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Astronomy, Department of, 1950-1951 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Athletic Association, 1947-1953 (Box 5, Folder 47-48)
  - Athletics, Harvard-Yale-Princeton Committee on, 1950-1951 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Audio-Visual Center, 1952-1953 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Bergen County, Yale Alumni Association of, 1947-1951 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Birmingham, Yale Alumni Association of, 1947-1949 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Boston, Yale Alumni Association of, 1948-1949 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Budget Committee, Yale University, 1947-1950 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Budget Drive, Yale University, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Buildings, use of, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Business Manager, Office of the, 1951-1953 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Central New York, Yale Club of, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - Central Ohio, Yale Club of, 1949-1951 (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - Chicago, Yale Club of, 1947-1953 (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - China Institute, 1949-1952 (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - Christian Association, 1949-1952 (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - Church of Christ in Yale University, 1949-1951 (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - Cincinnati, Yale Club of, 1947-1950 (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - Civil Defense, 1951-1953 (Box 6, Folder 65)
  - Class gift fund, 1949-1953 (Box 6, Folder 66)
  - Class insurance, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 67)
  - Class Reunion Bureau, 1948-1951 (Box 6, Folder 68)
  - Class Secretaries, undated (Box 6, Folder 69)
  - Class Secretaries Association, 1950-1953 (Box 6, Folder 70)
  - Class Secretaries Association: reports and minutes, 1945-1953 (Box 6, Folder 71)
  - Cleveland, Yale Alumni Association of, 1947-1950 (Box 6, Folder 72)
  - Colleges and Schools: other, 1949-1952 (Box 7, Folder 73-74)
  - Colorado, Yale Alumni Association of, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 75)
  - Columbia University, 1949-1952 (Box 7, Folder 76)
  - Congregational Churches, General Council of, 1951-1953 (Box 7, Folder 77)
  - Connecticut Hall: Hummel, Kimball, Orr, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 78)
  - Connecticut Hall: restoration of, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 79)
  - Connecticut Valley, Yale Club of Massachusetts, 1949-1951 (Box 7, Folder 80)
  - Coordinating Officer, Military, Naval and Air Affairs, 1949-1953 (Box 7, Folder 81-82)
  - Correspondence with Yale Classes, 1947-1953 (Box 7, Folder 83-84)
  - Country Day School, 1950-1952 (Box 8, Folder 85)
  - Courses and departments, 1949-1952 (Box 8, Folder 86)
  - Cuba, Yale Association in, 1948-1949 (Box 8, Folder 87)
  - Daily News, 1948-1952 (Box 8, Folder 88)
  - Dallas, Yale Club of, 1948-1949 (Box 8, Folder 89)
  - Davenport College, 1948-1951 (Box 8, Folder 90)
  - Dayton, Yale Club of, 1949 (Box 8, Folder 91)
  - Defense and Mobilization, Committee on, 1950-1951 (Box 8, Folder 92)
  - Delaware, Yale Alumni Association of, 1948-1950 (Box 8, Folder 93)
  - Divinity School, 1948-1953 (Box 8, Folder 94)
  - Donner, Robert, 1949 (Box 8, Folder 95)
  - Donner, Robert, 1950-1952 (Box 9, Folder 96)
  - Drama School, 1950-1953 (Box 9, Folder 97)
  - Dramatic Association, 1948-1950 (Box 9, Folder 98)
  - Dwight Hall, 1948-1953 (Box 9, Folder 99)
  - Eastern Fairfield County, Yale Club of, 1948-1951 (Box 9, Folder 100)
  - Economics, Department of, 1947-1952 (Box 9, Folder 101-102)
  - Educational supervision in the colleges, 1931-1948 (Box 9, Folder 103)
  - Emerson, Thomas I, 1948-1951 (Box 9, Folder 104)
  - Endowment and Gifts, Committee on, 1950-1952 (Box 9, Folder 105)
  - Engineering, School of, 1948-1953 (Box 9, Folder 106)
  - Enrolled students, 1948-1953 (Box 10, Folder 107)
  - Equipment, Office of, 1947-1950 (Box 10, Folder 108)
  - Erie, Yale Alumni Association of, 1949 (Box 10, Folder 109)
  - Eta Chapter of Zeta Psi Association, 1952-1953 (Box 10, Folder 110)
  - Expense account reports, 1947-1953 (Box 10, Folder 111)
  - Faculty appointments and retirements, 1953-1954 (Box 10, Folder 112)
  - Faculty Club, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 113)
  - Faculty deferment, 1950-1953 (Box 10, Folder 114)
  - Faculty lists, 1952-1953 (Box 10, Folder 115)
  - Faculty tea ushers, 1949-1950 (Box 10, Folder 116)
  - Fine Arts, School of, 1947-1951 (Box 10, Folder 117)
  - Foreign nationals, 1951-1953 (Box 10, Folder 119)
  - Forestry, School of, 1950-1953 (Box 10, Folder 120)
  - Freshman counselors, 1949-1953 (Box 10, Folder 121)
  - Geology, Department of, 1948-1952 (Box 10, Folder 122)
  - Gibbs, Josiah Willard, 1939 (Box 10, Folder 123)
  - Gifts, 1953 (Box 10, Folder 124)
  - Glee Club, 1948-1952 (Box 10, Folder 125)
  - Grace New Haven Community Hospital, 1953 (Box 10, Folder 126)
  - Graduate School, 1948-1953 (Box 10, Folder 127)
  - Greenwich, Yale Alumni Association of, 1947-1951 (Box 10, Folder 128)
  - Griswold, A. Whitney: correspondence, 1950-1953 (Box 10, Folder 129)
  - Griswold, A. Whitney: inauguration of, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 130)
  - Hartford, Yale Alumni Association of, 1947-1949 (Box 11, Folder 131)
  - Harvard University, 1947-1953 (Box 11, Folder 132)
  - Hawaii, Yale Alumni Association of, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 133)
  - Health, University Department of, 1951-1953 (Box 11, Folder 134)
  - History, Department of, 1947-1953 (Box 11, Folder 135)
  - Honorary Degrees, Committee on, 1947-1950 (Box 11, Folder 136)
  - Human Relations Council of New Haven, 1951-1953 (Box 11, Folder 137)
  - Important people, undated (Box 11, Folder 138)
  - Inland Empire, Yale Association of, 1947-1950 (Box 11, Folder 139)
  - Inquiries for jobs at Yale and elsewhere, 1951-1953 (Box 11, Folder 140)
  - Institute of Far Eastern Languages, 1950-1952 (Box 11, Folder 141)
  - Institute of International Studies, 1947-1951 (Box 11, Folder 142)
  - Kansas City, Yale Club of, 1947-1952 (Box 11, Folder 143)
  - Kentucky, Yale Alumni Association of, 1947-1951 (Box 11, Folder 144)
  - Law, School of, 1947-1953 (Box 11, Folder 145-146)
  - Library, 1948-1953 (Box 11, Folder 147)
  - Long Island, Yale Alumni Association of, 1949-1950 (Box 12, Folder 148)
  - Louisiana, Yale Alumni Association of, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 149)
  - Maryland, Yale Alumni Association of, 1949-1950 (Box 12, Folder 150)
  - Master of Arts in Teaching Program, 1952-1953 (Box 12, Folder 151)
  - Medicine, School of, 1947-1953 (Box 12, Folder 152)
  - Memorials: Committee on Memorial Quadrangle, 1947-1948 (Box 12, Folder 153)
  - Memorial Services, 1969-1972 (Box 12, Folder 153A)
  - Memphis, Yale Club of, 1947-1951 (Box 12, Folder 154)
  - Mercer County, Yale Club of, 1949-1951 (Box 12, Folder 155)
  - Miami, Yale Club of, 1948-1949 (Box 12, Folder 156)
  - Michigan, Yale Alumni Association of, 1947-1953 (Box 12, Folder 157)
  - Military and Naval Affairs, 1949-1952 (Box 12, Folder 158)
  - Military and Naval Affairs: Forty-first Strategic Infantry Unit, 1948-1950 (Box 12, Folder 159)
  - Military Science and Tactics, Department of, 1947-1953 (Box 12, Folder 160-161)
  - Miscellaneous conferences, 1947-1952 (Box 12, Folder 162-163)
  - Miscellaneous letters, 1947-1953 (Box 12, Folder 164)
  - Montclair, Yale Club of, 1948-1949 (Box 12, Folder 165)
  - Mory's Association, 1948-1953 (Box 12, Folder 166)
  - Music, School of, 1948-1953 (Box 13, Folder 167)
  - National Student Association, 1949-1953 (Box 13, Folder 168)
  - Naval Science and Tactics, Department of, 1949-1956 (Box 13, Folder 169)
  - Negroes, 1947-1949 (Box 13, Folder 170)
  - New Britain, Yale Club of, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 171)
  - New Haven, City of, 1952 (Box 13, Folder 172)
  - New Haven Colleges, 1951-1952 (Box 13, Folder 173)
  - New Haven, Yale Club of, 1947-1953 (Box 13, Folder 174-175)
  - News Bureau, 1947-1953 (Box 13, Folder 176)
  - New York, Yale Club of, 1947-1953 (Box 13, Folder 177-178)
  - Northeastern Institute, 1947-1953 (Box 14, Folder 179-180)
  - Northeastern New York, Yale Alumni Association of, 1947-1949 (Box 14, Folder 181)
  - Northwest, Yale Alumni Association of, 1947-1950 (Box 14, Folder 182)
  - Northern California, Yale Alumni Association of, 1947-1950 (Box 14, Folder 183)
  - Northwestern Connecticut, Yale Club of, 1947-1950 (Box 14, Folder 184)
  - North Georgia, Yale Club of, 1947-1949 (Box 14, Folder 185)
  - Nursing, School of, 1948-1953 (Box 14, Folder 186)
  - Oklahoma, Yale Club of, 1948-1949 (Box 14, Folder 187)
  - Oregon, Yale Alumni Association of, 1947-1953 (Box 14, Folder 188)
  - Organization Committee on University, 1951 (Box 14, Folder 189)
  - Peabody Museum, 1948-1951 (Box 14, Folder 190)
  - Personnel Office, 1948-1953 (Box 14, Folder 191)
  - Phi Beta Kappa, 1947-1953 (Box 14, Folder 192)
  - Philadelphia, Yale Club of, 1947-1952 (Box 14, Folder 193)
  - Physics, Department of, 1948-1951 (Box 15, Folder 194)
  - Pittsburgh, Yale Club of, 1947-1950 (Box 15, Folder 195)
  - Placement and vocational guidance, 1947-1951 (Box 15, Folder 196)
  - Placement service, 1947-1952 (Box 15, Folder 197)
  - Political Science, Department of, 1951-1952 (Box 15, Folder 198)
  - President, Assistant to, 1952-1953 (Box 15, Folder 199)
  - President, Memoranda to (Mr. Seymour), 1947-1950 (Box 15, Folder 200)
  - President's report, 1947-1952 (Box 15, Folder 201)
  - Princeton University, 1947-1950 (Box 15, Folder 202)
  - Professional School Alumni Publications, 1948-1951 (Box 15, Folder 203)
  - Projects, Committee on the Authorization of, 1948-1950 (Box 15, Folder 204)
  - Proposed fair educational practices legislation, 1951-1953 (Box 15, Folder 205)
  - Provost's Office, 1949-1953 (Box 15, Folder 206)
  - Publicity, 1947-1950 (Box 15, Folder 207)
  - Radio and television, 1951-1953 (Box 16, Folder 208)
  - Recommendations, letters of, 1940-1953 (Box 16, Folder 209-211)
  - Relations with other countries, 1947-1953 (Box 16, Folder 212)
  - Reprint of Mr.(Edward S.) Noyes' article, 1947 (Box 16, Folder 213)
  - Requisitions, 1951-1952 (Box 16, Folder 214)
  - Restaurant Institute, 1950-1953 (Box 16, Folder 215-216)
  - Restaurant Institute of Connecticut, 1947-1950 (Box 16, Folder 217)
  - Reunion booklet, 1945-1948 (Box 16, Folder 218)
  - Rhode Island, Yale Alumni Association of, 1948-1953 (Box 16, Folder 219)
  - River Plate, Yale Club of the, 1947 (Box 17, Folder 220)
  - Rostow incident, 1948 (Box 17, Folder 221)
  - R.O.T.C., Faculty Advisory Committee on, 1947-1953 (Box 17, Folder 222)
  - St.Louis, Yale Club of, 1947-1951 (Box 17, Folder 223)
  - Scholarship: fellows and loans, 1950-1951 (Box 17, Folder 224)
  - Scholarship: Memorial Campaign, 1948-1949 (Box 17, Folder 225)
  - Scholarship: student appointments, 1953-1954 (Box 17, Folder 226)
  - Selective Service, 1950-1951 (Box 17, Folder 227)
  - Service Bureaus, 1949-1952 (Box 17, Folder 228)
  - Seymour, President Charles, 1949-1951 (Box 17, Folder 229)
  - Shanghai, Yale Club of, 1948 (Box 17, Folder 230)
  - Sheffield Scientific School, 1947-1950 (Box 17, Folder 231)
  - Sociology, Department of, 1949-1951 (Box 17, Folder 232)
  - Southeastern Texas, Yale Club of, 1948-1949 (Box 17, Folder 233)
  - Southern California, Yale Club of, 1947-1950 (Box 17, Folder 234)
  - Southern Texas, Yale Club of, 1948-1949 (Box 17, Folder 235)
  - Summer sessions, 1949-1951 (Box 18, Folder 237)
  - Summit Country (Ohio), Yale Alumni Association of, 1951 (Box 18, Folder 238)
  - Topeka, Yale Club of, 1948-1949 (Box 18, Folder 239)
  - Transitory Application Conference, 1953 (Box 18, Folder 240)
  - Treasurer's Office, 1947-1953 (Box 18, Folder 241)
  - Tucson, Yale Club of, 1947-1950 (Box 18, Folder 242)
  - Undergraduate Activities, 1948-1953 (Box 18, Folder 243-244)
  - Undergraduate Activities, Dean of, 1951-1952 (Box 18, Folder 245)
  - University Development, Office of, 1948-1952 (Box 18, Folder 246)
  - Utah, Yale Club of, 1947 (Box 18, Folder 247)
  - Utica and vicinity, Yale Club of, 1948 (Box 18, Folder 248)
  - Virginia, Yale Club of, 1948-1952 (Box 18, Folder 249)
  - Visitors to Yale, 1948-1952 (Box 18, Folder 250)
  - War plans, 1950-1951 (Box 18, Folder 251)
  - Washington trips regarding military plans, 1950-1951 (Box 18, Folder 252)
  - Western New York, Yale Alumni Association of, 1949-1953 (Box 19, Folder 253)
  - Western North Carolina, Yale Alumni Association of, 1952 (Box 19, Folder 254)
  - Western Washington, Yale Alumni Association of, 1947-1953 (Box 19, Folder 255)
  - West Texas, Yale Club of, 1948-1949 (Box 19, Folder 256)
  - Wichita, Yale Club of, 1948 (Box 19, Folder 257)
  - Wiggin and Dana, 1953 (Box 19, Folder 258)
  - Worcester, Yale Club of, 1948-1949 (Box 19, Folder 259)
  - W.Y.B.C. Advisory Council, 1948-1950 (Box 19, Folder 260)
  - Yale College curriculum, 1947-1953 (Box 19, Folder 261)
  - Yale Corporation, 1947-1953 (Box 19, Folder 262)
  - Yale-Heidelberg Affiliation, 1947-1953 (Box 19, Folder 263)
  - Yale movie, 1948-1951 (Box 19, Folder 264)
  - Yale Review, 1947-1951 (Box 19, Folder 265)
  - Yale studies, 1945-1949 (Box 19, Folder 266)
  - Yale University Press, 1953 (Box 19, Folder 267)
- University Secretary: General Correspondence and Subject File, 1901-1972 1953-1971; Series II
  - A-general, 1953-1971 (Box 20, Folder 1-6)
  - Academic Freedom, 1953-1956,1962-1963,1966-1969 (Box 20, Folder 7-9)
  - Accounts, 1966-1969 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Acknowledgements: Sympathy, 1959-1961 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Acknowledgements: Sympathy, 1962-1965 (Box 21, Folder 12-14)
  - Addams, Jane Centennial, 1960 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Administration building, 1957-1958 (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Administrative data systems, 1968 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Admissions Board, 1953-1957 (Box 21, Folder 18-20)
  - Admissions Board, 1959-1960 (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - Admissions Board, 1963-1964 (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - Admissions Office, 1957-1966 (Box 22, Folder 23-27)
  - Admissions Office, 1966-1971 (Box 23, Folder 28-33)
  - Advertising Council, 1956-1958 (Box 24, Folder 34-35)
  - Africa, Yale Activities in, 1964-1968 (Box 24, Folder 36)
  - African-American Institute, 1969 (Box 24, Folder 37)
  - Afro-American Studies, 1969 (Box 24, Folder 38)
  - Air Science and Tactics, 1953-1957 (Box 24, Folder 39)
  - Alcohol Studies, Center of, 1956-1961 (Box 24, Folder 40-41)
  - "Alley Cats, Yale", 1971 (Box 24, Folder 42)
  - Alph Phi Omega, 1967-1968 (Box 24, Folder 43-44)
  - Alumni Affairs, 1967-1971 (Box 25, Folder 45-48)
  - Alumni Association and Clubs
    - 1954-1965 (Box 25, Folder 49-52)
    - 1965 (Box 26, Folder 53)
    - 1968-1971 (Box 26, Folder 54-56)
  - Alumni Board
    - 1953-1955 (Box 26, Folder 57-59)
    - 1955-1956 (Box 27, Folder 60-61)
    - 1955-1958 (Box 27, Folder 62)
    - 1955-1960 (Box 27, Folder 63)
    - 1958-1960 (Box 27, Folder 64)
    - 1960-1961 (Box 28, Folder 65)
    - 1960-1962 (Box 28, Folder 66)
    - 1961-1965 (Box 28, Folder 67-70)
    - 1965-1968 (Box 29, Folder 71-76)
    - 1968-1971 (Box 30, Folder 77-79)
  - Alumni Class Reunions, 1959-1963 (Box 30, Folder 80)
  - Alumni Commission, 1969-1970 (Box 30, Folder 81)
  - Alumni Council, 1953-1956 (Box 30, Folder 82-83)
  - Alumni Convocation, 1960-1961 (Box 30, Folder 84-85)
  - Alumni Day
    - 1954-1963 (Box 31, Folder 86-94)
    - 1964-1969 (Box 32, Folder 95-100)
  - Alumni Directory, 1967 (Box 32, Folder 101)
  - Alumni Fellows
    - 1922-1958 (Box 32, Folder 102-104)
    - 1959-1968 (Box 33, Folder 105-114)
    - 1969-1970 (Box 34, Folder 115-116)
  - Alumni Films, 1971 (Box 34, Folder 117)
  - Alumni Fund
    - 1953-1965 (Box 34, Folder 118-123)
    - 75th Anniversary, 1964 (Box 34, Folder 124)
    - 1964-1966 (Box 34, Folder 125-126)
    - 1966-1971 (Box 35, Folder 127-132)
  - Alumni Hall Tables, 1951 (Box 35, Folder 133)
  - Alumni House
    - 1946 (Box 35, Folder 134)
    - 1965-1967 (Box 35, Folder 135)
    - 1967-1971 (Box 36, Folder 136-140)
  - Alumni Magazine, 1954-1971 (Box 36, Folder 141-145)
  - Alumni Placement Service, 1964-1968 (Box 36, Folder 146-147)
  - Alumni Records and Clerical Bureau, 1953-1971 (Box 37, Folder 148-156)
  - Alumni Relations, 1953-1960, 1967 (Box 37, Folder 157-158)
  - Alumni Road Show, 1970 (Box 37, Folder 159)
  - Alumni Seminar, 1957-1970 (Box 38, Folder 160-173)
  - American Council on Education, 1967 (Box 39, Folder 174)
  - "American Education's Greatest Need" (A. Whitney Griswold), 1959 (Box 39, Folder 175)
  - American Philosophical Society, 1960 (Box 39, Folder 176)
  - American Scientific Education (A. Whitney Griswold), 1958 (Box 39, Folder 177)
  - American Studies, 1953-1958 (Box 39, Folder 178-179)
  - American University Union in Europe, 1917-1919 (Box 39, Folder 180)
  - Andrew, Rector, 1963 (Box 39, Folder 181)
  - Anthropology, 1967-1971 (Box 39, Folder 182)
  - Applications: job, 1953-1962 (Box 39, Folder 183)
  - Arbor Day, 1971 (Box 39, Folder 184)
  - Architectural Forum, 1957-1964 (Box 39, Folder 185)
  - Architectural policies, 1956-1966 (Box 40, Folder 186)
  - Archives, 1958-1963 (Box 40, Folder 187-189)
  - Archives, 1958-1963 (Box 40, Folder 190-192)
  - Area programs, 1968 (Box 40, Folder 193)
  - Army, 1964,1967-1969 (Box 40, Folder 194-196)
  - Arrests, 1960 (Box 40, Folder 197)
  - Art and Architecture, School of, 1954-1960 (Box 41, Folder 198)
  - Art and Architecture, School of, 1962-1971 (Box 41, Folder 199-208)
  - Art Gallery
    - 1928-1929 (Box 42, Folder 209)
    - 1953-1957 (Box 42, Folder 210)
    - 1953-1967 (Box 42, Folder 211)
    - 1958-1967 (Box 42, Folder 212-217)
    - 1969-1971 (Box 42, Folder 218-219)
  - Arts Council, New Haven, 1964-1966 (Box 43, Folder 220-221)
  - Arts and Sciences, Program for, 1961-1962 (Box 43, Folder 222)
  - Ashville School, 1958-1960,1964,1966 (Box 43, Folder 223-225)
  - Associate Secretary, Office of, 1964 (Box 43, Folder 226)
  - Association of Colleges in New England, 1967-1969 (Box 43, Folder 227)
  - Astronomy, 1956-1960,1963-1967 (Box 44, Folder 228-230)
  - Athletic Association
    - 1953-1965 (Box 44, Folder 231-234)
    - 1967 (Box 44, Folder 235)
    - 1969-1971 (Box 44, Folder 236-238)
  - Atomic Energy Series, 1958 (Box 44, Folder 239)
  - Audio Visual Center, 1954-1971 (Box 45, Folder 240-242)
  - Aurelian Society, 1961-1971 (Box 45, Folder 243-244)
  - "Autograph Letters and Engravings of Eminent Yale Men: Collection of,", undated (Box 45, Folder 245)
  - Aviation, 1967-1969 (Box 45, Folder 246)
  - B-general
    - 1954-1958 (Box 46, Folder 247)
    - 1960-1970 (Box 46, Folder 248-252)
  - Baccalaureate, 1968-1970 (Box 46, Folder 253)
  - Band, 1968-1969 (Box 46, Folder 254)
  - Banner publications, 1967-1971 (Box 46, Folder 255)
  - Banner, College, Graduate and Professional, 1953-1960 (Box 47, Folder 256)
  - Barnard sesquicentennial, 1961 (Box 47, Folder 257)
  - Battell Chapel, 1953 (Box 47, Folder 258)
  - Battell organ and chapel, 1970-1971 (Box 47, Folder 259)
  - Beinecke Library, 1962-1970 (Box 47, Folder 260-262)
  - Bellringers, Guild of, 1964-1967 (Box 47, Folder 263)